# Alexandru Reznic - Mobile Software Developer + Backend

- Languages:
  - o Russian native
  - o Romanian native
  - o English intermediate
- Contacts:
  - o reznic.a@gmail.com
  - https://t.me/reznic\_a
  - https://github.com/a-reznic
  - https://linkedin.com/in/reznic-a
  - https://stackoverflow.com/users/795616/reznic

Moldova, Chisinau. Prefer remote work

# Professional experience (16+ years)

Period	Role(Company)	Description
11.2021 - now [ <b>1y3m</b> ]	Senior Android Developer( <b>DataDrive</b> )	ELD(Electronic logging device) is a technology used in the trucking industry to track and record a commercial driver's hours of service. Developed from scratch, Kotlin, Clean architecture, MVVM, Koin, Room. Custom theme, support portrait, landscape, phones and tablets.
07.2020 - 11.2021 [ <b>1y4m</b> ]	Kotlin Backend Developer( <b>Orange</b> )	Orange Money Romania, BFF microservice, Refactoring and Performance of GraphQL microservice. Kotlin, Kafka, Coroutines. Improve requests time from 4s to 2s. Setup TeamCity pipeline.
02.2018 - 07.2020 [ <b>2y5m</b> ]	Team Lead Android Developer( <b>LogoSoft</b> )	I have led team of 3 people, developed from scratch traft, Single Activity, MVVM, Room, Retrofit, Git Flow, Second app com.vezubr.driver refactoring. Setup Gitlab CI.
10.2014 - 01.2018 [ <b>3y2m</b> ]	Backend/Frontend Developer( <b>Reznic Software</b> )	App for tourism B2B flintour and Backoffice application for tourism backoffice Spring, Tomcat, Angular 1.  Communicated with the client for certain projects to understand the requirements and expectations.
02.2014 - 10.2014 [ <b>9m</b> ]	Android Developer( <b>Livemile</b> )	Nookbank - Mobile Client Bank app

Period	Role(Company)	Description
04.2011 - 02.2014 [ <b>3y</b> ]	CEO/Team Lead/Android Developer( <b>Reznic Software</b> )	I have led team of 6 people, 4 developers, 1 game designer, 1 graphical designer. Published about 30 games on Google Play. Socket server for Dominoes and Yahtzee games.
04.2010 - 04.2011 [ <b>1y</b> ]	CEO/Android Developer( <b>Ndroidz Software</b> )	Published about 10 games on Google Play
04.2009 - 04.2010 [ <b>1y</b> ]	J2ME/Android Developer( <b>MobiTeam/Creafire</b> )	Develop J2ME games, android games
02.2008 - 04.2009 [ <b>1y2m</b> ]	Java Developer( <b>Vivat Consulting</b> )	J2EE Developer, implemented user interfaces, implemented business logic, performed JUnit tests, changed reports structure, export data to Microsoft Excel file.
06.2006 - 01.2008 [ <b>1y7m</b> ]	J2ME Developer( <b>Meedia</b> <b>Mobile</b> )	Develop J2ME games, android games

## Skills

Programming Languages	Kotlin, Java, Dart, SQL
Frameworks & Libraries	Android, Flutter, Spring Boot, Kafka, GraphQL,Jasper Reports, Junit, Mockito
Databases	PostgreSQL, SQLite
Services	GitLab, GitHub, Docker, Jenkins, GitLab Cl, Jira, Youtrack
IDE	Android Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse

#### Android

- Clean Architecture, MVVM, MVP
- Room, Realm
- Kotlin Coroutines, RxJava
- Retrofit, OKHTTP, remote logs with Kibana
- Android Jetpack (Navigation, Live Data, View Models)
- Firebase (Crashlytics, Admob, Notification, App Distribution, Analytics, Firestore, Remote Config)

- Self-published apps in Google Play
- Obfuscation Proguard
- CI/CD, Git, Gradle, Unit Testing

#### Java-Related

- Languages: Java, Kotlin(last 5 years only Kotlin)
- Spring Boot:
  - o Core: DI, Bean Post Processor, Aspect
  - o Web: REST Controller
  - Security: Basic, Oauth, JWT tokens
  - o Data: Entity, Repository, Transaction, Flyway migration
- Kafka
- GraphQL
- Tomcat
- Jasper Reports
- Tests: JUnit, Mockito

## Summary

Highly motivated and enthusiastic Senior Mobile Development Engineer with more than 16 years of software engineering experience in the development of entire android apps, games and back-end services. I try to follow development trends and often learn new languages and technologies.

In my free time I play computer games, improve my knowledge in English, listening podcasts.

## **Projects**

Flutter - Taxi App

reznicsoftware.com

flintour.com

bo.flintour.com

### Education

• 2008 Bachelor of Informatics Ion Creanga University